<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>steve.agilitynerd.com</title><link href="http://steve.agilitynerd.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://steve.agilitynerd.com/feeds/stuff.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://steve.agilitynerd.com/</id><updated>2015-11-15T15:00:00-06:00</updated><entry><title>Use iTunes to Play Your Forgotten Gems</title><link href="http://steve.agilitynerd.com/use-itunes-to-play-your-forgotten-gems.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-11-15T15:00:00-06:00</updated><author><name>Steve Schwarz</name></author><id>tag:steve.agilitynerd.com,2015-11-15:use-itunes-to-play-your-forgotten-gems.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have about 7,000 songs in my iTunes music collection and I've always been disappointed with the shuffle feature of iTunes; it seems to bring up only a small sample of those songs. I thought I'd share a Smart Playlist that I use to find the songs that I might have forgotten about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you haven't used Smart Playlists before here are &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://support.apple.com/kb/PH19487?locale=en_US"&gt;Apple's instructions for creating a Smart Playlist&lt;/a&gt;. Once you create a new one you can configure it like I have below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="iTunesNeverPlayed" src="/static/images/iTunesNeverPlayed.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are three rules:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select everything that has only been played less than one time (i.e. never played).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Limit the selections to Music.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Skip any tracks that have been skipped more than twice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I called this playlist 'Never Played' and used it to find a few hundred tracks that iTunes shuffle never played. As they were playing I put the ones I liked into other playlists, rated them or skipped them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course you can adjust this playlist or make others like it to fit your needs. Once I've heard all the songs in my Library at least once I could edit this list and change the 'Plays is less than' to '2' and keep incrementing my way through my lesser heard tracks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you like to use stars/ratings to create playlists of your favorites you could create a Smart Playlist to find tracks played less than 5 times and not yet rated:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="iTunesUnratedRarelyPlayed" src="/static/images/iTunesUnratedRarelyPlayed.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I hope this gives you some ideas for how to use Smart Playlists to explore your music collection!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="iTunes"></category><category term="music"></category></entry><entry><title>Ai Weiwei Sunflower Seeds</title><link href="http://steve.agilitynerd.com/ai-weiwei-sunflower-seeds.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-11-30T14:00:00-06:00</updated><author><name>Steve Schwarz</name></author><id>tag:steve.agilitynerd.com,2013-11-30:ai-weiwei-sunflower-seeds.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My birthday present this year from Nancy was something I was thrilled to get: some Ai Weiwei Sunflower seeds. Earlier this year I saw &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://youtu.be/gcRodOfu_s8"&gt;this fascinating documentary (now on YouTube)&lt;/a&gt; about this unique Chinese modern artist and social/political critic (&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ai_Weiwei"&gt;Ai Weiwei on wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="AiWeiWeiSunflowerSeeds" src="/static/images/AiWeiWeiSunflowerSeeds.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was captivated by his &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.tate.org.uk/whats-on/tate-modern/exhibition/unilever-series-ai-weiwei-sunflower-seeds"&gt;Sunflower Seeds installation at the Tate Modern in London&lt;/a&gt; when it was presented in film. The use of millions of Chinese porcelan sunflower seeds, craftsman produced and each unique, brilliantly captures our conflicting views of China and it's people. My description doesn't really do the exhibition justice. Here is an excerpt from &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.tate.org.uk/whats-on/tate-modern/exhibition/unilever-series-ai-weiwei/interpretation-text"&gt;the Tate's interpretation text&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
Ai Weiwei’s Sunflower Seeds challenges our first impressions: what you see is not what you see, and what you see is not what it means. The sculptural installation is made up of what appear to be millions of sunflower seed husks, apparently identical but actually unique. Although they look realistic, each seed is made out of porcelain. And far from being industrially produced, ‘readymade’ or found objects, they have been intricately hand-crafted by hundreds of skilled artisans. Poured into the interior of the Turbine Hall’s vast industrial space, the seeds form a seemingly infinite landscape. The precious nature of the material, the effort of production and the narrative and personal content make this work a powerful commentary on the human condition.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was surprised to see that many of the seeds are available for purchase after the close of the exhibition. I mentioned that to Nancy and the rest is birthday history. It is great to have a few little pieces of this monumental installation.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="birthday"></category><category term="art"></category></entry><entry><title>My FLOR House Pet Customer Support Saga</title><link href="http://steve.agilitynerd.com/my-flor-house-pet-customer-support-saga.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-03-08T14:00:00-06:00</updated><author><name>Steve Schwarz</name></author><id>tag:steve.agilitynerd.com,2012-03-08:my-flor-house-pet-customer-support-saga.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Five or so years ago I put in &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.flor.com"&gt;FLOR&lt;/a&gt; carpet tiles in my living room. I liked the color scheme and figured they would be long lasting. I installed them as a floating floor - the oak floor is visible around the edges of the carpet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="thumbnail clear"&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/37642750@N00/8539276253/" title="FLOR House Pet in the Living Room by mrpandmilo, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8384/8539276253_d02ebdcfd6.jpg" width="500" height="334" alt="FLOR House Pet in the Living Room"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I also liked that I could pull them up in case of dog accidents or mess making on my part. All was well for a few years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I found that I couldn't reposition the tiles after pulling them up - they wouldn't stay in place. I had to buy/use more &lt;cite&gt;FLOR-dots&lt;/cite&gt; (the sticky plastic tape squares that stick the tiles to one another) each time I pulled a tile up for cleaning. It was getting expensive to keep buying more dots. Pretty soon 50% of my tiles had gaps on the edges and would go flying with any dog activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I went to contact customer support. I don't like spending time on the phone waiting for customer support. So when I found no email addresses on the website... (really?) I filled out the contact customer support form. I received an automated response that I'd hear back in two days. Two weeks later no reply - filled it out again - same automated response. Waited a week and still no reply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I finally called and was passed along to someone's voice mail. I was really not happy at this point. The next day I received a call from a customer support person. I explained my problem and my unhappiness with my customer support experience. They apologized and told me that they had been having problems with the old formulation of FLOR-dots not sticking to the backing of the House Pet tiles... Clearly what I was experiencing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the nice woman (wish I could remember her name) had a whole pile of the new dots sent out to me in a couple days at no charge. It took about an hour to pull up the tiles that had gaps and re-dot them. No gaps and no flying tiles!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First off, thanks to FLOR for &amp;quot;making it right&amp;quot;. Secondly, in this age of always connected people, it should be easy for customers to contact a company electronically - email addresses should be visible and easily accessible on the website. The spam argument doesn't cut it - companies have to suck it up and handle their email. Lastly, if a company really feels the need to have an impersonal contact form, someone has to actually be responsible for handling the contacts that come through it!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="dogs"></category><category term="floor"></category></entry><entry><title>My Late 1970s Colnago Super Road Bike</title><link href="http://steve.agilitynerd.com/my-late-1970s-colnago-super-road-bike.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-02-04T00:18:00-06:00</updated><author><name>Steve Schwarz</name></author><id>tag:steve.agilitynerd.com,2012-02-04:my-late-1970s-colnago-super-road-bike.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I worked my way through high school and college as a bicycle mechanic at
the &amp;quot;The Cycle Scene&amp;quot; bike shop down the street from our house starting
in the late 1970s. I was a bike nerd back then and spent most of the
money I earned on bike parts. During that time I built my dream bike:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Img_0906" src="/static/images/img_0906.jpg" /&gt; &lt;img alt="Img_0864-1" src="/static/images/img_0864-1.jpg" /&gt; &lt;img alt="Img_0867-1" src="/static/images/img_0867-1.jpg" /&gt; &lt;img alt="Img_0869-1" src="/static/images/img_0869-1.jpg" /&gt; &lt;img alt="Img_0870-1" src="/static/images/img_0870-1.jpg" /&gt; &lt;img alt="Img_0871-1" src="/static/images/img_0871-1.jpg" /&gt; &lt;img alt="Img_0872-1" src="/static/images/img_0872-1.jpg" /&gt; &lt;img alt="Img_0874-1" src="/static/images/img_0874-1.jpg" /&gt; &lt;img alt="Img_0873-1" src="/static/images/img_0873-1.jpg" /&gt; &lt;img alt="Img_0877-1" src="/static/images/img_0877-1.jpg" /&gt; &lt;img alt="Img_0878-1" src="/static/images/img_0878-1.jpg" /&gt; &lt;img alt="Img_0879-1" src="/static/images/img_0879-1.jpg" /&gt; &lt;img alt="Img_0880-1" src="/static/images/img_0880-1.jpg" /&gt; &lt;img alt="Img_0882-1" src="/static/images/img_0882-1.jpg" /&gt; &lt;img alt="Img_0881-1" src="/static/images/img_0881-1.jpg" /&gt; &lt;img alt="Img_0884-1" src="/static/images/img_0884-1.jpg" /&gt; &lt;img alt="Img_0887-1" src="/static/images/img_0887-1.jpg" /&gt; &lt;img alt="Img_0888-1" src="/static/images/img_0888-1.jpg" /&gt; &lt;img alt="Img_0890-1" src="/static/images/img_0890-1.jpg" /&gt; &lt;img alt="Img_0891-1" src="/static/images/img_0891-1.jpg" /&gt; &lt;img alt="Img_0892-1" src="/static/images/img_0892-1.jpg" /&gt; &lt;img alt="Img_0893-1" src="/static/images/img_0893-1.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I can't remember when I bought the frame, it was 77 or 78. The bike has
had a number of mods over it's lifetime. I built several sets of wheels
around the small flange Campy Nuovo hubs. I rode sewups/tubulars for a
while. I had the current wheels built by Performance bikes in the 1990s
and they probably have less than 100 miles on them. I had lost the bike
bug by then...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the current list parts list for any old school road bike fans
out there:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;63 cm Black Colnago Super frameset&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Campagnolo Nuovo Headset&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cinelli Record Stem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cinelli Giro D'Italia bars&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hand stitched leather bar wraps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Galli Ti (titanium bolt) short reach brakes with Mathauser brake pads&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Colnago &amp;quot;panto&amp;quot; engraved Campagnolo Nuovo brake levers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Campagnolo Nuovo shifters and Super Record front deraileur&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Colnago engraved Campagnolo Super Record crankset with 46/42
chainrings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;O.M.A.S. sealed bearing bottom bracket with titanium spindle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Weyless sealed bearing pedals with Colnago decalled alloy toe clips,
Binda straps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Campagnolo Super Record rear deraileur with red anodyzed aluminum
Bullseye sealed bearing pulleys&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Colnago engraved Campagnolo Nuovo(?) seat post&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avocet saddle (I've probably had a dozen saddles on this bike over
the years)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Performance dual seat mount bottle cages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sedis chain (had a nicer chain at one point)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shimano alloy freewheel (many Italian freewheels over the years)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wheels are Campagnolo Nuovo small flange with chrome butted DT
spokes, black anodized aluminum nipples, Mavic MA40 700c hard
anodized (clincher) rims with 1&amp;quot; Performance tires.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yellow frame fit Silca pump.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yellow teflon lined cable housings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mount for Cateye computer with cadence and rear wheel speedometer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It needs a complete overhaul it hasn't had any maintenance in 15+ years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took it for a quick spin around the block probably five years ago and
I still love how stiff it is for a large steel tube frame. Each push of
the pedals and the bike lept foward. Thinking about it almost makes me
want to do the overhaul and ride it again...&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="cycling"></category></entry><entry><title>Coolest Christmas Present</title><link href="http://steve.agilitynerd.com/coolest-christmas-present.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-12-18T21:51:00-06:00</updated><author><name>Steve Schwarz</name></author><id>tag:steve.agilitynerd.com,2010-12-18:coolest-christmas-present.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Nancy got me this present for Christmas! I laughed out loud!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="thumbnail"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="780365587" src="/static/images/780365587.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</summary><category term="christmas"></category></entry></feed>